When one falls, another brings him home.
Taking Chance is a drama, war, tv movie film directed by Ross Katz.
Michael Strobl, a volunteer military escort accompanies the body of Lance Cpl.
Chance Phelps to his hometown in Wyoming.
LtCol Mike Strobl, played by Kevin Bacon.
Charlie Fitts, played by Tom Aldredge.
Nate Strobl, played by Nicholas Art.
Chris Phelps, played by Blanche Baker.
Gary Hargrove, played by Guy Boyd.
Tom Garrett, played by Gordon Clapp.
Taking Chance is a 2009 American historical drama television film
directed by Ross Katz, from a screenplay by former U.S.
Marine officer Michael Strobl and Katz, based on the journal of the same
title kept by Strobl, who also served as military consultant.
Kevin Bacon's portrayal won him a Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Miniseries or Television Film and a Screen Actors
Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Miniseries or Television Movie, among others.
Taking Chance premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on January 16, 2009,
and aired on HBO in the United States on February 21, 2009.
The film received generally favorable reviews from critics.
At the 61st Primetime Emmy Awards, it earned ten nominations, such as Outstanding Television Movie and Outstanding Lead Actor in a
Miniseries or Movie for Bacon, and won one for Outstanding Single-Camera Picture Editing for a Miniseries or a Movie.
The film explores themes of war crimes, warlord,
iraq, based on true story, war victim.
The tone is emotional.